Jason Macfarlane

Front-end Engineer

Front-end engineer with 9+ years of experience developing and designing interactive, scalable, and accessible websites and web applications. Experienced working with Vue, Nuxt, Angular, Node.js, and more, and can quickly adapt to other frameworks and technologies.

Experience

Front End Engineer

Spring Financial, Vancouver, BC (remote) — May 2021 – Present (subsidiary of Canada Drives)

Most recently built and led the Spring Financial website redesign/rebranding and the Foundation application flow – an *almost* completely automated way for customers to apply and get approved for Spring's credit building product.

Some other tasks:

- Built the customer dashboard with SMS verification
- Integrated and designed live chat (powered by Salesforce)
- Coordinate deployments with DevOps engineer
- A/B testing
- Code reviews
- Refactored legacy code
- Mentored junior developers

Web Developer

Works Design, Toronto, ON — November 2016 – May 2021

Worked alongside top-tier designers to build responsive, WCAG Level AA compliant, interactive websites for big companies. These websites include annual reports, sustainability reports and corporate websites.

- · Project specifics include:
 - · Cross-browser testing in IE11, Edge, Chrome, Firefox and Safari
 - · UI/UX planning and recommendations
- Clients include: Newmont, New Gold, GTAA, Corby Spirits and Wine, Maple Leaf Foods, Sherritt
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS & SCSS, Javascript, PHP, MySQL, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Webpack

Owner & Developer

Web Code Tools - April 2014 - Present

Developed and designed a web code generator for beginning web developers to learn HTML, CSS and Schema.org markup to improve SEO and user experience.

- #1 Product of the Day on Product Hunt May 21, 2017
- 60K+ users, 185K+ page-views (and growing) per month as of November 2022
- Technologies used: Nuxt, Vue, Node.js, HTML, SCSS, Google Analytics, GTM, Ezoic

Location

Toronto, ON

Phone

+1 (613) 857-0720

Email

jasonmac5@gmail.com

Website

iasonmacfarlane.dev

GitHub

github.com/JasonMacfarlane

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jason-macfarlane

Languages

English, French

Skills

Vue

Nuxt

Node.js

Angular

TypeScript & JavaScript

CSS & SCSS

HTML

GraphQL

PHP

MySQL

MongoDB

Git

Jason Macfarlane

Front-end Engineer

Owner & Developer

Personalized phone case e-commerce store — July 2019 – April 2020 https://github.com/JasonMacfarlane/wallet-case-personalization-store

Designed and developed a Shopify store selling personalized wallet phone cases. Used Angular, Angular Material and the Shopify JS SDK, Shopify Admin GraphQL API and the Shopify Storefront API. This approach allowed for maximum flexibility, like custom checkout pages and tailored landing pages based on the user's interests from targeted ads.

- Developed a product customizer with preview using Angular, TypeScript and the Node.js image processing library Sharp. This method allowed customers to upload an image of their choice and preview it on a phone case to increase conversion rate and to give the customer an accurate representation of their product.
- Developed custom checkout pages and integrated Stripe and PayPal due to the limitations of the regular Shopify plan not allowing checkout page modifications.
- Successfully tested early versions with real customers and sales using Facebook ads.

Education

Algonquin College, Ottawa, ON - Computer Engineering

Location

Toronto, ON

Phone

+1 (613) 857-0720

Email

jasonmac5@gmail.com

Website

jasonmacfarlane.dev

GitHub

github.com/JasonMacfarlane

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jason-macfarlane

Languages

English, French

Skills

Vue

Nuxt

Node.js

Angular

TypeScript & JavaScript

CSS & SCSS

HTML

GraphQL

PHP

MySQL

MongoDB

Git